The footage your are about to watch is of a sensitive nature
and may not be suitable for all viewers but it is for the glory of God.
58 year-old Mr Omotosho Kareem, from Oyo State, Nigeria,
has come to The SCOAN with the deadly problem of throat cancer.
This is the medical report from Lagos University Teaching Hospital,
showing the diagnosis of his ailment.
Imagine how this problem has affected his daily life,
not being able to eat or speak, and the terrible odour that would be coming out of his mouth.
He has come to The SCOAN with the belief that Jesus Christ can supernaturally heal him
and bring life in abundance.
The camera zooms into Omotoshu Kareem's mouth,
showing a severe spreading of the throat cancer,
and swelling to the extent that it has closed the passage of his mouth.
The pain is unbearable.
Only a divine touch from Jesus Christ can reverse this problem.
Mr Omotosho Kareem awaits at the prayer line in hope for Jesus Christ to divinely come to his aid
and rescue him from the claws of sickness.
Prophet T.B. Joshua ministers prayer in the name of Jesus Christ
and the power of healing falls upon him
and breaks the yoke of throat cancer in his life.
TESTIMONY TIME
Praise the Lord!
Praise the Living Jesus!
My name is Mr Kareem Omotosho.
I came to The SCOAN to thank God for what He has done in my life.
If not for the God of T.B. Joshua, I would not have been able to talk like this.
I would have joined them in the graveyard.
Back in December 2015, it started as if a small bone got stuck in my throat.
I started running from one place to another.
I went to many hospitals, including Lagos University Teaching Hospital.
When I got there, they diagnosed it and told me that it was cancer of the throat and mouth.
I said, "Wow, what will I do?"
One day, I was at the doctor, and he told me that this growth was fast growing
and that they had no option than to operate on my throat and insert a pipe.
They had to do it because I couldn't use my mouth to do anything.
I went home and decided that I have to come to The SCOAN.
At that time, what were the things you could no longer do with your mouth? Were you able to talk?
How difficult was it at that time?
I could not eat anything or swallow.
I could only take watery pap ( liquid food).
Were you able to talk?
I couldn't talk. I even smelt bad.
When I entered a bus, people would complain that something was smelling.
They would say, "Who brought something rotten?"
When I entered a bus, I would sit by the window,
so I could put my mouth outside because of the smell.
Many people rejected me because they knew, and even I knew that I was going to die.
There was no way out; I vomited blood every day.
I then decided to come to The SCOAN.
I thank the God of T.B. Joshua.
When I was placed on the prayer line, Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed for me.
Instantly, the saliva that had been uncontrollable stopped.
Shall we put out hands together for Jesus Christ!
Before you came to The SCOAN to receive prayer from the man of God,
Prophet TB Joshua, at the prayer line, you were constantly dropping saliva uncontrollably?
I always carried a towel with me because it was uncontrollable. I tried to control it, but couldn't.
It came out like water every minute.
The first thing that happened to me - the saliva stopped.
My body calmed down.
I thought that pieces of the meat (tumour) would come out but instead it melted away.
I didn't see it any longer. That's how the cancer disappeared from my life.
Hallelujah!
We can see you talking now.
So you mean you could not even express yourself?
I couldn't.
If I wanted to communicate to anyone around, I had to write it on a piece of paper.
I couldn't talk.
And all the pain you used to have?-
It was not a small pain.
What you watched - you would understand what I am saying.
The pain was so much I couldn't control it.
I thank God today that everything (cancer) is over in my life.
See the left side of the screen.
See how terrible it was. It was spreading from inside the mouth down to the throat.
He could no longer do things for himself.
Eating was a problem, he could not talk.
Pain and the agony day and night.
He said that when he was placed at the prayer line, the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua,
prayed for him, as you can see on the left side of the screen. That's the same man.
After the prayer by the man of God, he was completely set free.
Right now, can you open your mouth and let us see?
Wow!
Mr Kareem Omotosho - Healed Of Throat And Mouth Cancer
Once again, put your hands together for Jesus Christ!
Before and After
Look at the left side of your screen - that was his condition when he first came to The SCOAN.
Right now on the right side of the screen, you can see his testimony.
All the cancerous growth is gone.
Now his mouth is normal and his throat is free of cancer.
Now you can eat very well?
I can eat, I can do anything.
Once again, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
People all over the world and the people that are here - in any situation you find yourself,
please run to God because it is only in God that you can find hope.
I had lost hope.
My family had said that they wanted to take me to the village.
They knew it would be cheaper to put me in a vehicle to take me to my village
than dying here and then take me to my village.
So they wanted to take me there.
If not that I ran to God, what would I have done?
In any situation, problem, just run to God and you will be saved.
Thank You, Jesus!
To God be the glory! Watch your screen!
Viewers out there, you can see the comparison between the shot on the left side of the screen
and on the right side of the Screen.
This man testified that no one around him believed that he would survive.
He himself had the thought and the belief in his heart that he was going to die
because he was no longer functioning like someone living in the land of the living.
Glory be to God, he came to the right place, at the right time and met the right person -
the anointed Prophet of God who waved his hand towards him and the miracle happened.
Now, he is alive today to share that testimony.
Put your hands together for Jesus!
Mr Kareem Omotosho - Healed Of Throat And Mouth Cancer
My advice to the whole world is that when there is a problem, don't look at people.
Just run to God because Jesus Christ is the only hope.
So, please run to God.
Jesus Christ is the only hope.
The Bible says that Jesus Christ is the answer to all fundamental issues of life -
be it sickness, setback, poverty, failure, barrenness.
Whatever it is, run to Jesus and you will receive a solution.
We thank God Almighty for your life.
We also want to encourage you that the healing you have received is for the salvation of your soul.
The only way you can maintain this healing is to make the Word of God the standard for your life.
We pray that God Almighty will give you the inner grace to make God's Word the standard of your life,
in Jesus' name!
Amen.
Thank you. Once again, put your hands together for Jesus!
STANDARD FOR LIFE
I want to take up the issue of the gentleman who testified here.
With the case of cancer. I want us to look again at that case.
If cancer on any part of the body remains uncured,
how can you manage the one on the tongue that would not have the grace to enjoy the air.
You understand that when something somewhere is bleeding, it's always difficult to cure
because air is healing; you can take it up.
He did not have grace for the air
but he is cured by mere waving hand.
Your situation will be cured!
Amen!
Your situation is cured!
If you have that faith, take one - your situation will be cured!
Amen!
Your situation is cured!
Which one is yours?
Your situation will be cured!
Amen!
Your situation is cured!
You can't claim the two.
You can't belong to the two.
You belong to one.
You have to stand up now. Let me know the one you are waiting for.
If you stand up, when the situation is not yours, you sit down.
When the situation is yours, you stand up.
Your situation will be cured!
Amen!
Your situation is cured!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated. Let's watch!
Mr Omotosho Kareem awaits at the prayer line
in hope for Jesus Christ to divinely come to his aid
and rescue him from the claws of sickness.
Prophet T.B. Joshua ministers prayer in the name of Jesus Christ,
and the power of healing falls upon him
and breaks the yoke of throat cancer in his life.
You can see it clear.
Can you see it clear ?
This is the kind of thing you are supposed to put on your phone
and that will enhance your faith.
Before and After
Any time you are disturbed, you woud remember the Healer.
There is a time to be disturbed, and a time to be happy.
A time to be what? - (disturbed)
And a time to be what? - (happy)
Yes, any time you are disturbed, you play it to yourself
so that you would be able to cope with hard and good moments.
Tell your neighbour:
So that you would be able to cope with hard and good moments.
Tell your neighbor again:
I can't hear you.
So that you would be able to cope with hard and good moments.
Again !
It's only like that, you see me...
Can you see?
Hard
Good
Good and Hard
Don't say, until you have pain in your leg, before you realise that you are going through good and hard times.
Don't say, until there is no money in the pocket,
before you recognise that you are going through hard and good times.
Don't say, until you have no food on the table,
before you recognise that life is all about hard and good moments.
Tell your neighbour:
Life is all about hard and good moments.
I can't hear you!
Again!
Life is all about hard and good moments.
How do we know this?
We know this through the thoughts in our hearts.
There is a conflict going on.
There is a conflict going on in your heart.
As you are sitting down, there is a conflict going on in your heart.
"No", "yes".
"Ok, let me go!"
"When it is 12 o'clock, I will leave!"
The thought of your heart.
You know your heart is a prayer room.
Tell your neighbour:
A Christian's heart is a prayer room.
A believer's heart is a prayer room.
It is a prayer room; that is the altar.
If your prayer is not from that place, whatever you are saying, you are deceiving yourself.
The prayer must come from the altar, prayer room.
If your prayer is not from your heart, you are just talking to the air.
This is why you doubt yourself because what you are saying is not from your heart.
You are bound to doubt yourself.
"In the name of Jesus, heal me!"
The doubt comes when you are not healed because that prayer is not from your heart.
If your prayer comes from the prayer room - the heart - you cannot doubt yourself.
You would believe!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Am I talking to you?
A believer's heart is the prayer room.
So, you keep doubting yourself.
Anytime you take a decision, doubt comes -
whether to do it or not to do it;
whether to pay the money or not to pay the money.
You get confused.
It's about the decision; it's about doubt.
When it's about decision, doubt comes
because what you are saying is not from your heart.
Your heart is the prayer room, the altar.
When the prayer is not from the altar, whatever you are saying, you are saying it to the air.
That's what we call, saying words, praying prayer.
So, now..
Stop measuring your Christian life by your situation.
In this case, your situation should not mislead you.
That you are poor does not mean you cannot be a Christian.
We always attach that, whatever happens to you - sin.
No!
Sin also brings reproach - we agree!
But, sometimes, a situation like this can be used to draw you close (to God).
You should agree with me that it's your situation that brought you here today.
If you didn't have that situation, you would have unlikely come here.
Our situation strengthens our desire and determination for Christ.
Ok, now.
You have seen that gentleman, after he has been to many places.
He has spent all his fortune.
He could not eat, he could not talk.
They wanted to operate on him in order to pass the food through the stomach.
So then, he came to Jesus.
If there is anything that can draw your attention to Christ most, this is it.
No amount of message...
We have many theologians here.
We have many people that have gone through the Bible many times in a year.
This is a human being just like you.
Assume you are in this situation.
You cannot talk; you cannot eat.
This had become a curse, it was no longer a sickness.
There is a difference between sickness and curse.
If a situation becomes a curse, who can stop the curse?
Only Jesus.
Sickness and disease can be treated by human beings, medical doctors,
you, whatever, tablets, drugs.
When you take it, if it's sickness, it will be treated.
This is the meaning of 'Doctor treats; God heals'.
Sickness demands for treatment.
Curse demands for healing.
Who can heal? Only God.
Doctors can treat - you can treat as a medical doctor.
This one, the more he is treated, the more the damage.
Let's see the healing
before and after.
Mr Kareem Omotosho - Healed Of Throat And Mouth Cancer
Before and After
Can you see?
So over to you - dentists, doctors; you can meet a man like him.
Begin to take care of the stitch and wash his tougue.
Sometimes when our teeth are too bad, it can cause anything.
Can we ask you - how manage?
After the healing, the first thing I noticed was that the uncontrollable saliva stopped.
When you were facing this problem, were you able to eat or talk?
I could not eat or do anything.
Even whenever I drank a little bit of water, it felt like fire.
I could not talk.
Listen to that.
What did the doctor tell you before you run to the church?
They said there was nothing they could do about it.
They called me and told me that the cancerous growth was growing fast.
They said they needed to operate on my throat and insert a pipe.
They noticed that I couldn't breathe well any longer.
They wanted to operate on my throat and insert a pipe for me to be breathing through.
After the prayer here, the first day, the second day,
the first week, the second week, what happened? Can you tell us the procedure, the process?
After the prayer, the excess saliva stopped and I started seeing changes.
Everything started drying up.
Food I could not eat before, I started asking them to give me.
People around me were surprised that I was eating.
How the whole thing disappeared, I didn't realise it; it just dried up like that.
I could not talk before. When I wanted to communicate, I had to write.
Now, I can talk.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Mr Kareem Omotosho - Healed Of Throat And Mouth Cancer
You see?
Thank you.